I am an advanced high school graduate (with one year's worth of college credit) from California that is interested in working on a project in Switzerland for the summer. An active participant in the Silicon Valley's bustling computer industry, I hope to bring the spirit and knowledge of Bay Area entrepreneurship to Europe. My unique experiences surrounding computer science, entrepreneurship, and education technology include starting a school centered about Design Thinking, teaching high school students programming basics, and organizing numerous hackathons of over 1200 students. The projects that I work on currently are focused on frontend web development with tools like AngularJS, libraries like TransitJS,

with emphasis on high aesthetic quality and design principles.

LinkedIn in.yashplorer.com
GitHub git.yashplorer.com
Email yashplorer@gmail.com

I. Web Development

A. Skills

- 1. AngularJS
- 2. NodeJS
- 3. HTML5
- 4. CSS3
- 5. Responsive Web Design
- 6. Many libraries, like ChartJS

B. Projects

Plexis Chat app to branch conversations outward based on content
 Feed Your Net Dashboard of social relationships and tools to reignite them

buzzMe
 Network that for anonymous complimenting among members of an group
 Budget
 An AngularJS app to manage transactions with monthly budgetary constraints
 Itinerary
 An AngularJS app to manage a trip with highly custom details and weather

II. Graphic Design

A. Skills

- 1. Photoshop
- 2. Illustrator
- 3. Photo Editing
- 4. Icons
- 5. Logos

B. Projects

1. UNICEF Developed poster for a UNICEF club's fundraising event

Interact District 5150 Transformed Interact's online presence with full graphics set
 Rong Hwa Designed the scholarship for a local Millbrae organization

4. San Mateo High Created most digital promotional material for SMHS' clubs and leadership

III. Educating & Volunteerism

A. Skills

- 1. Leadership
- 2. Event Planning
- 3. Teaching
- 4. Fundraising
- 5. Marketing

B. Projects

1. Interact District 5150 Served as web master of Rotary International's Interact District 5150

2. StudentRND Organized many high school hackathons with Seattle-based nonprofit

3. Design Tech High Advise as a student board member of an emerging charter school

4. Model UN Served as vice president and participated in international policy debate

5. ARK Founded the Acts of Random Kindness Club at San Mateo

6. Programming Club Teach programming as President of club to underclassmen

Yash Plorer

Altruistic, Athletic, Opinionated Student Leader, Designer, and Programmer

yashplorer@gmail.com

Experience

Founder at REDesign High School

March 2014 - Present (1 year 2 months)

Most American students attend public school, public schools that are mainly financed by taxpayer dollars. Unfortunately, although many taxpayers and their children (the students) have a say in how their local school's work, it is not often that their opinions, ideas, and desires ever are expressed. REDesign High School hopes to change this. By submitting a little bit of information in the form on this page with simply expressed ideas or thoughts about his or her school, a taxpayer or student may have his or her ideas expressed. The content of this form is sent to a passionate individual or the leadership department (whose main function is to communicate between the student body and the administration) in a school that will write a formal letter regarding the thought such that it may be considered by the administration.

Hackathon Hacker and Business Conceptualist at My World

February 2012 - Present (3 years 3 months)

I've made this occupation to organize the many projects that I've worked on at Hackathons and business courses.

Projects

Plexis

June 2013 to Present

Members: Yash Plorer, Case Sandberg, Shadi Barhoumi, Chris Gervang, Conner Swann

A rather large team was put together at Under 20 Codeday at YetiZen Innovation Labs, organized by StudentRND, and by the Thiel Foundation's Under 20 Summit. We have put together a chat service called plexis (incorrectly-spelled plexus). It is a web app that allows a user to branch out conversations to talk about two or more things at once with one person. We are honored to say that we did 'win' the Codeday by receiving the "Top Overall Award" for our application.

Feed Your Net

June 2013 to Present

Members: Yash Plorer, Shadi Barhoumi, Preetha Ram, Ruslan Smirnov, Bob Schoenthal, Chris Gervang, Case Sandberg, Conner Swann

Feed Your Net was built at Startup Weekend Silicon Valley. FYN was made to keep a user connected with people he or she met. A team of 10 members was put together at the SAP Lab venue, 3 of business,

3 designers, and 4 developers. We have put together a web app that reminds you to contact people after meeting them so you stay in touch.

buzzMe

February 2013 to Present

Members: Yash Plorer, Michelle Kang, Shadi Barhoumi, Chris Gervang, Sara Evensen

A small team was put together at CodeDay SF February at Splunk organized by StudentRND, and successfully worked on a project called buzz.ME, a complimentary website. The web application was a compliment service based on schools for students to complement anonymously on one another.

Scarecrow's Revenge

May 2012 to August 2012

Members: Yash Plorer, Shadi Barhoumi

A friend of mine developed an application for the Android mobile platform, and came to me for assistance in the field of graphic design. For the application, I made graphics produced with tools such as Photoshop and Illustrator.

Easy, Efficient Cookies

May 2012 to June 2012

Members: Yash Plorer

EEC was an entrepreneurship course's business model in which a team and I created drafted a business plan for a "game-changing" product. We produced the plan for a grocery shopping companion mobile application and created a formal pitch aimed at venture capitalists.

Sujit & Co.

February 2012 to March 2012

Members: Yash Plorer, Sushmita Sujit, Jacqueline Pei

Sujit & Co. was small business hosted by Franklin Templeton Investments that was founded by the Junior Achievement Program. The company successfully made profit off selling privacy screen protectors for iPhone 4th generation products. As Vice President of Production, I led the company in the order of our product and the packaging for sales. I also assisted the Marketing department.

Organizations

Programming Club of San Mateo

President

January 2012 to Present

I assist in the running of San Mateo High School's Programming Club, the only source of computer science education for the school prior to my bringing Computer Science in 2014. In a class-like environment, I educate students in the basics of computer science logistics with languages such as JavaScript, HTML, and CSS. We also perform applications with drones.

Acts of Random Kindness Club of San Mateo

President

July 2014 to Present

Model United Nations Club of San Mateo

Vice President

July 2014 to Present

Design Tech High School

Student Board Member

July 2013 to Present

Instructors from my education in Design Thinking education appreciated my passion and enthusiasm about the movement, and invited me to sit on the board of a developing high school. I serve as a voting student board member for Design Tech High School (opening Autumn of 2014) and advise the board on their decisions from a student perspective. Design Tech takes a new approach to education, more information here: dtechhs.org

StudentRND

Education Technology Evangelist // Organizer

June 2013 to Present

I bring computer science education to students by hosting and helping events called Hackathons with a variety of organizations including StudentRND. Notable hackathons that I've helped run include HSHacks, CodeDay, and Hacking Generation Y. I often work in fields of student outreach and volunteer management.

Interact District 5150 & Club of San Mateo

Senior Webmaster & District Representative

July 2013 to June 2014

Interact is a subsidiary of Rotary International, a service organization. I have engaged with Interact since 2010, and was given a position of webmaster starting 2012. In 2013, I completely rewrote the web platform of the Interact Club from the ground up. All code on smhsinteract.org is authored by me.

Honors and Awards

Honourable Mention for BuzzMe

StundentRND

February 2013

We were almost awarded "Best App" at Codeday SF, but we came as runner-up. A description is documented in Splunk's blog: http://blogs.splunk.com/2013/02/19/studentrnds-1st-code-day-sf-success/

Top Overall Award for Plexis

StudentRND

June 2013

We were awarded Top Overall [highest honor] at the Under 20 Codeday for our plexis chat project.

Rotary PRLS Graduate

Rotary District 5150 PRLS Board

December 2014

Languages

German

Spanish

Hindi

English

(Elementary proficiency)

(Limited working proficiency)

(Limited working proficiency)

(Native or bilingual proficiency)

Skills & Expertise

CSS

Graphic Design

Web Design

Photoshop

Adobe Photoshop

Publicity

Mac OS X

Buisness

Keynote

HTML 5

Adobe Indesign

JavaScript

Web Development

Press Releases

OS X

InDesign

User Interface Design

Social Media

Public Speaking

Event Planning

Leadership

Design Thinking

jQuery

Java

Python

Time Management

Teaching

Photography

Public Relations

Social Media Marketing

Social Networking

Communication

Nonprofits

Fundraising

Volunteer Management

Leadership Development

Finance

iWork

Entrepreneurship

Illustrator

HTML

Courses

San Mateo High School

European History AP **Environmental Science** AP English Language AP Spanish Language and Culture AP Calculus AB AP Calculus BC AP Government and Politics AP English Literature AP Computer Science A AP Macroeconomics AP Physics I AP

Education

San Mateo High School

2011 - 2015

Rotary International

Potential Rotary Leadership, 2012 - 2014

Gifted and Talented Education

Entrepreneurship and Design Thinking, 2012 - 2013

College of San Mateo

Finite Mathematics and Intermediate Algebra, 2012 - 2012

Interests

Business, Computer Science, Design

Yash Plorer

Altruistic, Athletic, Opinionated Student Leader, Designer, and Programmer

yashplorer@gmail.com



Contact Yash on LinkedIn